時は戦国、乱世の時代。
からくり人の住むジパング国では群雄割拠して合戦に明け暮れ、
からくり武芸者たちも勝利と栄光を目指してしのぎを削っていた。
そしていま、からくり武芸者ナンバー１を目指す、とてつもないヒーローが誕生した！
ムサシ、見参でござるだス！
からくり剣豪伝ムサシロード
男はいつでも　世界の真ん中で
いちばん　強くなる日を
AH! AH! 夢見て
心の刃　大空にふりかざし
冒険の旅の　幕を開ける
ジパング国を　さすらう剣豪
その名　からくりびと　ムサシ
GO! FIGHT!
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　昨日よりも　今日　強い
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
明日は　輝くぞ
鍔迫り合いの音が
眩しい人生
戦い　思い切りと　静けさと
BUGEI! 二刀流　ムサシ
みけんが　きらめいた　ムサシ！！
무사시 일행은 적의 본거지를 찾기 위해 세토 내해에 들어가지만, 거기서 기다리고 있던 건 신겐과 켄신이었다.
Musashi and others went into Seto Inland Sea to find the base of the enemy, but Shingen and Kenshin were waiting for them.
맞받아친 무사시 일행. 그러나 합체한 신겐신의 힘 앞에서 고전을 면치 못한다.
Musashi and others attacked in return, but they ended up having a hard fight between the combined Shingenshin.
요염한 모습
카라쿠리 변화이오
Charming Outlook
Karakuri Shift
무사시 놈들이 달아나게 두었다고?
You let them run away?
정말 면목이 없습니다.
We deeply apologize.
저 혼자서라면 확실히 해치웠을 수 있었을 테지만, 이 신겐이라는 놈이 방해해서...
I would have finished them if I was alone, but that Shingen guy got in my way and...
뭔 소리냐! 내 공훈을 빼앗고자 한 건 네 쪽이잖나!
What are you talking about?! You're the one who tried to take all my achievements!
-잘도 지껄인다! 네가 멍청해서다!
-뭔 하찮은 소리를 지껄이냐!
-멍청한 소리 마라!
-Say all what you want, but it's all because you're a fool!
-What kind of nonsense is that?!
-Don't be stupid!
용서를!
Forgive us!
이 다음에는 목숨은 없다. 당분간 반성하고 있어라.
I won't let you alive next time. Reflect on yourselves.
노부나가 님.
Mr. Nobunaga.
-한조.
-무사시 일행의 처리는 이 제게 맡겨 주십시오.
-Hanzō.
-Please leave me with finishing Musashi and others.
그래. 좋다. 다만...
Yes, good. But...
실패는 하지 않습니다. 그럼!
I do not fail. Then!
일단 방해자를 처리하고 국왕의 의자에 앉을 것이다.
Let me deal with hindrances first, and I'll sit on the seat of the king only after that.
료마의 배로 도움을 받은 무사시 일행은 세토 내해의 작은 섬에서 떨어지게 되었다.
After being helped by Ryoma and his ship, Musashi and others split at a small island in Seto Inland Sea.
료마 씨! 신세졌소!
Mr. Ryoma! Thank you-dasu!
그럼 일단 어딘가에 묵을 곳을 찾아봅시다.
Let's look for a place to stay first.
그러자. 나 느긋하게 목욕탕에 들어가고 싶어.
Good idea. I want to take a rest in a bath.
온천이 좋지! 나, 최근 어깨가 뻐근해서!
Hot springs would be good! My shoulders are stiff lately.
그럴 수 있으면 최고겠네!
That would be the best!
그래그래!
Right, right!
뭔 소리입니까. 그런 여관이 이 작은 섬에 있을 리가 없잖아요. 정말...
What are you talking about? There's no way an inn like that would exist on this small island. Really...
다들! 갈라져!
Everyone, scatter!
우리에게 느긋하게 쉴 틈도 안 주겠다는 건가!
Are they not going to allow us even a short break?
젠장! 이대로는 끝이 없어!
Damn! There's no end to this!
어서 처리하고 온천 가자!
Get rid of them as soon as possible and let's go to a hot spring!
알아!
I know that!
케로키치!
Kerokichi!
케로키치! 올챙이 폭탄 발사!
Kerokichi! Fire tadpole bombs!
괜찮소, 오츠루?
Are you alright-dasu, Otsuru?
짚신 끈이 끊어졌어.
A string of my straw sandal is broken.
그럼 내가 업어 주겠소!
Then I'll carry you on my back-dasu!
응!
Yes!
사이가 좋은 건 좋은 것이구나?
Being friendly is good, eh?
당연하오. 우리는 사람들이 부러워하는 애인들이니까.
Of course-dasu! We're lovers that everyone envies-dasu!
저런, 무사시 씨도 참, 오츠루 부끄럽게!
No, Mr. Musashi, you're making me shy!
그렇소?
Is that so-dasu?
흥. 놀고 있는 것도 지금뿐이다.
Hmph. Your playtime is over.
무사시 씨, 무서워!
Mr. Musashi, I'm scared!
내게 맡기시오!
Leave it to me-dasu!
이천일류 섬광권!
Niten'ichiryū: Flash Sword!
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
젠장!
Damn!
난 불사신이라 했을 터!
I told you I'm invincible!
젠장!
Damn!
끝장이다!
Time to finish!
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
괜찮냐, 무사시!
Are you alright, Musashi?
지라이얀! 살았소!
Jiraiyan! You saved me-dasu!
케로키치!
Kerokichi!
감히 어디서!
How dare you!
지라이얀! 널 살려둔 게 내 실수였던 듯 하구나!
Jiraiyan! It seems that it was my mistake of letting you alive!
바로 그거다! 케로키치, 해라!
That's right! Kerokichi, do it!
다시 오겠다!
I'll come again!
더는 안 와도 되오!
You can stop coming back-dasu!
무사시 씨, 괜찮아?
Mr. Musashi, are you okay?
물론이오!
Of course-dasu!
젠장! 나도 저런 불사신의 갑옷을 원하오.
Damn, I want an invincible armor like that-dasu.
적은 어딨냐!
Where's the enemy?!
코지로도 참, 엄청 늦게 왔어.
Kojirō, you're very late.
저런, 기껏 내 멋진 모습을 보여주겠다고 생각했더니 안타깝군.
My, I was thinking to show my cool looks, and too bad.
그 대신, 모두가 기뻐할 사람을 데리고 왔습니다.
Instead of that, I brought a person that will make everyone happy.
어? 제니가탄 두목이오?
Huh? Is it Boss Zenigatan-dasu?
국왕 전하지?
It's the Highness, right?
아니, 세토 내해의 귀여운 아이 아니야?
Could it be a cute girl living around Seto Inland Sea?
단고집 주인이지?
Is it dango store's boss?
아니, 아닙니다.
No, you're wrong.
센히메 님이 걱정되어 에도토피아에서 급히 왔습니다.
I hurried my way from Edotopia because I was worried about Senhime.
여러분은 별로 기뻐하지 않는 것 같군요.
It seems that you people aren't really happy that I'm here.
-몰랐어!
-기뻐!
-I didn't know!
-We're happy!
누구냐!
Who's there?!
괴물인가!
A monster?!
나는 이 섬의 수호신이다. 섬을 어지럽히러 온 자를 지옥에 보내러 왔다.
I am the protector of this island. I am here to send whoever came to disturb the island.
목숨을 원한다면 어서 이 섬에서 떠나라!
If you value your lives, then leave this island immediately!
우리는 섬을 어지럽히러 온 게 아니야!
We're not here to disturb the island!
세상을 어지럽히는 악을 퇴치하러 왔다!
We're here to expel the evil that disturbs the world!
어라, 아이들이잖아.
Oh, they're children.
미안해. 너희들이 그 괴물의 친구라고 생각했어.
I'm sorry. I thought you were that monster's friend.
괴물이라는 것은 메가톤성 말입니까.
Do you mean Megaton Castle by monster?
그렇습니다.
That's right.
요즘 일이년, 이 주변 바다를 휩쓸고 다녀서 낚시도 불가능하게 되었습니다.
In recent years, it's been ravaging through the bordering sea, and we couldn't even go fishing.
이 중에는, 섬을 버리고 도시로 나간 사람도 있습니다.
Some people left the island and went to big cities.
정말 못됐어!
How cruel!
내게 맡기시오. 꼭 해치워 주겠소!
Leave it to me-dasu. I'll deal with them-dasu!
별로 신뢰가 안 가는데.
You don't look so dependable...
뭐, 어느 정도 믿음직스럽지 못한 면이 있지만, 저희는 메가톤성을 퇴치하러 에도토피아에서 왔습니다. 걱정하실 필요 없습니다.
Well, he doesn't look very dependable, but anyway, we came from Edotopia to get rid of Megaton Castle. Do not worry.
감사드립니다. 그것과 관계된 이야기지만, 사무라이 씨들을 별실에 모시고 싶습니다.
Thank you. I'd like to invite you samurais to a different room to discuss something about that.
좋습니다.
Alright.
예.
Good.
응.
Right.
그렇소.
dasu.
이건 선조에게서 대대로 전해지는 카라 별에서 온 구세주가 남기고 간 고문서입니다.
This is an old document handed down from our ancestors which is left by the saviors from Planet Kara.
카라 별? 하늘에 떠 있는 별 말입니까.
Planet Kara? Are you talking about the one floating on the sky?
먼 옛날, 하늘의 부주에 탄 카라인이 이 오노고로 섬에 왔다고 합니다.
They say that a long time ago, Kara people riding on the Floating Ship of Sky came to this Onogoro Island.
즉, 우주인입니까?
Are you saying that they're aliens?
우주인?
Aliens?
그 쯤, 오노고노 섬의 사람들은 두려운 괴물에 시달리고 있었다고 합니다.
Back then, the people of Onogoro Island were suffering from a fearful monster.
그 때, 하늘의 부주에서 강림한 카라 별의 사람이 이걸 퇴치해서 이 섬에 평화가 되돌아왔습니다.
That time, people from Planet Kara, descended from the Floating Ship of Sky, exterminated those, letting peace return.
이 오노고로 섬의 사람들이 고통받는 때, 용자가 동방에서 와서 범고래의 입에서 신의 갑주를 얻어 악을 물리치리라.
When the people of Onogoro Island suffer, brave people will come from the east,
acquire the armor of gods from the Mouth of Orc, and drive away the evil.
지금 저희 오노고로 섬 사람들은 고통받고 있습니다. 그리고 동쪽에서 용자인 당신들이 왔습니다.
We the people of Onogoro Island are suffering. And brave people, you, have came from the east.
예고된 대로라는 말씀이십니까.
Just like the prophecy said, right?
그러나 괴물을 쓰러트리는 데에는 신의 갑주가 필요합니다.
But you will need the armor of gods in order to take the monster down.
어? 갑주가 있소? 나, 한조에게 지지 않을 무적의 갑주를 원하오!
Huh? Are there armors-dasu? I want an armor that will let me not be defeated by Hanzō-dasu!
그거 얼마이오?
How expensive is that-dasu?
공짜입니다.
It's free.
아싸! 나, 공짜는 뭐든 좋소!
Yay! I like whatever that's free-dasu!
그러나 갑주를 손에 넣기 위해서는 범고래의 입에 들어가야만 합니다.
But you will have to enter the Mouth of Orc in order to claim those armors.
범고래의 입이오?
The Mouth of Orc-dasu?
갑주를 손에 넣을 수 있을 것인가? 질풍노도의 후반을 기다려라!
Will they be able to get the armors? Wait for the stormy latter half!
카라쿠리 검호전 무사시 로드
Karakuri Kengouden: Musashi Road
이 아래가 범고래의 입입니다.
Below here is the Mouth of Orc.
엄청 높소. 여기서 내려가오?
This is very high-dasu! Are we going down from this place-dasu?
아니, 여기서는 무리입니다. 해면에서 올라오는 강풍 때문에 날라가버리고 맙니다.
No, it's impossible from here. Because of a strong wind from the seaside, you'll be thrown away.
그럼 어떻게 저기까지 가오?
Then, how can we go there-dasu?
배로 갈 수밖에 없습니다.
You have to use a ship.
건너편의 곶에서 배에 타, 해류를 타고 범고래의 입까지 다다를 수 있습니다.
You will ride a ship from a cape on the other side, follow the water current, and reach the Mouth of Orc.
그러나 범고래의 입에서는 해류가 강하게 부딪히고 있어서, 기회를 놓치면 바위에 부딪혀서 배는 엉망이 됩니다.
But the current crashes strongly into the Mouth of Orc, thus the ship will be broken into pieces if you don't make it.
조심하세요!
Please be careful!
죽으면 안 돼!
Do not die!
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
다들 힘내!
Everyone, do your best!
밧줄을 놓습니다!
We're letting the rope go!
그런 곳에서 죽으면 용서 못 해!
I won't forgive you if you die there!
코지로!
Kojirō!
여러분, 상처는 없습니까.
Everyone, are you hurt?
상처는 없어도, 나, 무겁소.
I'm not hurt, but it's heavy-dasu.
그래도 마침 좋은 곳에 통나무가 있어서 살았습니다.
But still, we live because there's a log in an awesome place.
통나무가 아니야! 케로키치 혀야!
It's not a log! It's Kerokichi's tongue!
케로키치! 이대로 범고래의 입까지 혀를 늘려!
Kerokichi! Extend your tongue into the Mouth of Orc!
뭐야, 처음부터 그랬으면 간단했잖아!
Hey, it could've been easier if you did that at the first place!
그래도 케로키치 씨, 힘들어 보여요.
But Mr. Kerokichi looks painful.
해냈소!
We did it-dasu!
난 갑주를 포기할게! 셋이서 가!
I'll give up the armor! You three can go by yourselves!
지라이얀! 포기하면 안 되오! 여기에 오시오!
Jiraiyan, you can't give up-dasu! Come here-dasu!
이제 시간이 없어! 무사시, 발밑을 봐!
There isn't enough time! Musashi, look below you!
아까보다 물이 들어왔소.
The water's flowing in-dasu.
만조인가.
High tide...
무사시 님, 어서 갑주를 손에 놓지 않으면 이 동굴에서 나가지 못하게 됩니다.
Mr. Musashi, unless we claim the armors soon, we won't be able to get out of the cave.
알겠소.
Got it-dasu.
다들 꼭 갑주를 찾아내!
Everyone! Find the armor no matter what!
정신 차렸구나, 케로키치.
You woke up, Kerokichi.
난 갑주는 필요 없어.
I don't need armors.
네가 있으니까.
Because I have you.
해골이 가득이오...
So many skulls-dasu...
다수의 무예가가 소문을 듣고 이 동굴에 들어온 것 같군요.
It seems that numerous martial artists came into this cave, hearing that rumor.
그래도 대부분이 관문을 못 넘고 죽고 말았다.
But most of them didn't make it through, and died.
보아하니 전설은 진짜 같구나.
It seems that the legend is true.
잘도 그런 상황에서 침착하고 있소.
You guys really are trying your best to look calm, in a situation like this-dasu.
저런, 이건 곤란하군요.
Well, excuse us.
빛이 있소!
There's a light-dasu!
와, 크오!
Woah, this is big-dasu!
본 적도 없는 모습을 보아하니 분명 우주인일 것입니다.
Judging from the look that I never saw before, it must be an alien.
그래도 갑주는 어디에도 없군요.
But, I can't see an armor around here.
역시 전설뿐인 것인가...
Is it only a legend, after all?
뭐, 기껏 왔으니...
Well, we're here, so...
노부나가 놈들을 해치울 수 있도록. 그리고 오츠루하고 결혼할 수 있도록.
Let us finish Nobunaga and others. Let me marry Otsuru.
음, 소리에 반응하는 장치가 설치되어 있었던 것 같군요.
It seems that there was a sound-reactive device installed.
좋소! 가 보오!
Alright! Let's go-dasu!
뭔 짓이오, 코지로!
What was that for-dasu, Kojirō?!
미안. 난 생쥐에 약해서...
Sorry. I'm weak to rats...
무사시 님! 코지로 님!
Mr. Musashi! Mr. Kojirō!
이 빛 가운데에 서니, 뭔가 이상한 감정이 들끓어 오릅니다.
Standing in the middle of this light, a strange feeling is arising.
이상한 감정이라니?
A strange feeling?
그래, 마치 어머님의 품에 안긴 느낌의.
Just like as if I'm embraced in the bosom of my mother.
더 말해 볼까요?
Should I explain more?
-그럼 나도.
-나도.
-Then, me too.
-Me too.
용자들이여, 기다리고 있었다. 옳은 마음을 가진 자만이 이 곳에 올 수 있다.
I was waiting for you, brave ones. Only the ones with the mind of justice can reach here.
이, 이게 무엇이오?
W- what is this-dasu?
(겐토쿠: 현덕, 유비의 자)
(Gentoku: Japanese pronunciation of Xuande, the courtesy name of Liu Bei)
현덕의 갑주.
Armor of Gentoku.
(칸우: 관우)
관우의 갑주.
(Kan'u: Guan Yu; served Liu Bei)
Armor of Kanu.
(초히: 장비)
장비의 갑주.
(Chōhi: Zhang Fei; served Liu Bei)
Armor of Chohi.
그리고 그대에게는 뇌명환을 건네 주겠다.
(raimei: thunder)
And, you will be granted Raimeimaru.
그 갑주, 옳은 마음으로 악을 쓰러트리고자 할 때 나타나지만, 보통의 배에 달하는 에너지를 소모한다는 것을 잊지 말지어다.
The armor will show itself when you're about to exterminate the evil with the spirit of justice,
but do not forget that it will drain your energy twice as fast.
위험했소!
That was close-dasu!
저건!
Look!
센히메 님!
Senhime!
무사시 씨!
Mr. Musashi!
미안, 다들. 내가 지켜야 했는데...
I'm sorry. I couldn't protect them...
기다리고 있었다, 무사시, 코지로, 주베. 셋이서 한꺼번에 저 세상에 보내 주겠다!
I was waiting for you, Musashi, Kojirō, and Jūbee. You three are going to the other world this instant!
비겁하오, 한조!
That's cowardly, Hanzō!
비겁해? 그건 언제라도 듣는 소리지.
Cowardly? I hear that a lot.
그 틀려먹은 근성을 때려고쳐 주겠소!
I'll beat your twisted guts into shape-dasu!
칼을 버려라, 무사시!
Drop your swords, Musashi!
악한 마음을 향한 분노가 들끓어오르오!
The rage towards evil mind is boiling-dasu!
카라쿠리 변화! 겐토쿠 아머!
Karakuri Shift! Gentoku Armor!
무사시! 언제 그런 갑주를!
Musashi! When did you get that armor?!
카라쿠리 변화! 칸우 아머!
Karakuri Shift! Kanu Armor!
어, 코지로까지!
Even you, Kojirō?!
카라쿠리 변화! 초히 아머!
Karakuri Shift! Chohi Armor!
주베까지 갑주를!
Even Jūbee got an armor!
한조! 각오하시오!
Hanzō! Prepare yourself-dasu!
나 혼자에게 셋이서 덤비다니 비겁하다!
Three against one is cowardly!
흥! 네게 그런 소리 들을 거라고는 생각도 못 했소!
Hmph! I never thought we'd be hearing that from you-dasu!
그래라!
Yeah, right!
오늘은 이쯤에서 봐 주겠다!
I'll let you go for today!
흥! 잘하는 것도 없는 주제에 뭔 소리이오.
Hmph! A big talk for an unskilled-dasu!
자, 다들, 저녁이야!
Here are your dinners!
우와, 맛있소! 갑주를 입고 싸우니 배가 고프오!
So delicious-dasu! Fighting in armors makes me hungry-dasu!
그래도 정말 멋진 갑주야!
Anyway, your armors look so cool!
응, 나, 감동했어!
Yeah, I was moved!
주베 씨, 더 드실래요?
Mr. Jūbee, do you need more?
아, 감사합니다. 부탁드립니다.
I'd like more. Thank you.
잘 먹었다! 케로키치, 많이 먹어라!
That was good! Kerokichi, you should eat a lot, too!
음, 전투 후의 한 잔의 차는 아주 그만이구나.
A cup of tea after a battle is tremendous.
저런, 코지로도 참, 골목 할배같아!
Kojirō, you sound like an old man on a side street!
아니, 그렇습니까.
Oh, do you think so?
숙적 한조는 아깝게도 달아났다. 그러나 무사시 일행은 무적의 갑주를 손에 넣어서 용기 100배가 되었다.
Their enemy Hanzō has regrettably ran away.
But with the invincible armors, Musashi and others were encouraged by hundredfold.
육도마왕 노부나가의 야망을 깨뜨릴 때까지, 가라, 싸워라, 무사시! 그게 사내의 전성기이다!
Until you destroy the ambition of Nobunaga the Rikudomaoh, go, fight, Musashi! That's the heyday of a man!
싸우고 맞았어
I fought and I got beaten
코피 쓩이야 랑데부
Nosebleed drips rendezvous
나도 지지 않으려 한발!
I can't lose, so take my blow!
핀치 펀치로 대역전
Pinch! Punch! I won by reversal
다음 시간 즐거운
Next is delightful lunchtime
급식일 텐데
But it's not delightful today
선생님의 벼락이
The thunder of my teacher
나한테만 떨어져 왔어
only hit me and nobody else
사정을 말해도
I tried to explain
들어주지 않는 채
But he won't listen
어떻게 해도 역시
Now whatever I do
눈물이 나오고 말아
I end up crying
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
완전 맛없어
it tastes totally bad
울면서 밥먹으면
Don't cry when you eat, or
왠지 안타까워
you'll feel downhearted
우리는 겐나이 씨라는 발명가에게 잠수함을 만들어 달라고 부탁했소.
We asked an inventor named Mr. Gennai to make a submarine for us-dasu.
그래도 그 할아버지, 호색하오. 오센짱하고 오츠루의 수영복 모습을 보여달라고 하오.
But that old man is lewd-dasu. He wants to see Osenchan and Otsuru in swimsuits-dasu.
그래도, 뭐, 잠수함도 완성되어서 우리는 메가톤성에 침입하오!
Well, whatever, the submarine is complete and we invade into Megaton Castle-dasu!
다음 이야기! 파도타는 겐나이 발명왕이오
Next story! Surfing Gennai is the Invention King
질풍노도의 잠수함이오!
It's a stormy submarine-dasu!
다음 이야기
파도타는 겐나이
발명왕이오
기대하세요!
Next Episode
Surfing Gennai
is the Invention King
Look forwards for it!